Guide to the Yale University's 300th Anniversary Commemoration Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of the Tercentennial Office, circa 1995-2001; Accession 2002-A-093
  - HISTORY AND ARCHIVES SUBCOMMITTEE
    - Hillman and Kersey (Box 9, Folder 413)
    - Wirthlin (Box 9, Folder 414)
  - Tercentennial Research Files
    - Research File Directory (Box 10, Folder 415)
    - Yale Corporation Trustees (Box 10, Folder 416)
    - Campaign for Yale 300 Years Research (Box 10, Folder 417)
    - Class of ‘45W (Box 10, Folder 418)
    - Early Yale Engineers (Box 10, Folder 419)
    - OPA Brief History of Yale (Box 10, Folder 420)
    - Preparing for Yale's fourth Century (Box 10, Folder 421)
    - Seminal Events (Box 10, Folder 422)
    - Yale Facts (Box 10, Folder 423)
    - Yale Firsts (Box 10, Folder 424)
    - Yale Football History (Box 10, Folder 425)
    - Yale Harvard Game (Box 10, Folder 426)
    - US Patented Yale Owned Research (Box 10, Folder 427)
    - Yale Quotes (Box 10, Folder 428)
    - Yale's Role in the Education of American Leaders (Box 10, Folder 429)
    - Yale Timeline/ 300 Years Research (Box 10, Folder 430)
    - Yale Greats/Top 30 (Box 10, Folder 431)
    - Yale Presidents (Box 10, Folder 432)
    - Yale Signers of the Constitution (Box 10, Folder 433)
    - African AmericansArt and Architecture (Box 10, Folder 434)
    - Academia English Literature (Box 10, Folder 435)
    - Business Economics and Investing (Box 10, Folder 436)
    - Divinity School (Box 10, Folder 437)
    - Entertainment Music and Drama (Box 10, Folder 438)
    - Forestry and Environmental Studies (Box 10, Folder 439)
    - Law Government and American History (Box 10, Folder 440)
    - Research: Political (Box 10, Folder 441)
    - Science and Technology (Box 10, Folder 442)
    - Medical, Nursing and EPH (Box 10, Folder 443)
    - Publications (Box 10, Folder 444)
    - Sports and Athletics (Box 10, Folder 445)
    - Master Classes/Ideas and Articles (Box 10, Folder 446)
    - Master Classes Cont. (Box 10, Folder 447)
    - OPA List of Notable Alumni (Box 10, Folder 448)
    - John Calhoun (Box 10, Folder 449)
    - Walter Camp (Box 10, Folder 450)
    - Charter Signing Pale (Box 10, Folder 451)
    - Class of 1778 (Box 10, Folder 452)
    - Jonathan Edwards (Box 10, Folder 453)
    - Duke Ellington (Box 10, Folder 454)
    - A. Bartlett Giamatti (Box 10, Folder 455)
    - Nathan Hale (Box 10, Folder 456)
    - Kelley Books Summary (Box 10, Folder 457)
    - Fredrick Koch (Box 10, Folder 458)
    - Pierson's Research Documents (Box 10, Folder 459)
    - Cole Porter (Box 10, Folder 460)
    - Roger Sherman (Box 10, Folder 461)
    - Noah Webster (Box 10, Folder 462)
    - Eli Whitney (Box 10, Folder 463)
    - Yale Signers of the Declaration of Independence (Box 10, Folder 464)
    - New Haven Mayors (Box 10, Folder 465)
    - Bios of Yale Governors (sitting) (Box 10, Folder 466)
    - Prominent Alumni
      - A (Box 11, Folder 467)
      - B (Box 11, Folder 468)
      - C (Box 11, Folder 469)
      - D (Box 11, Folder 470)
      - E-F (Box 11, Folder 471)
      - G (Box 11, Folder 472)
      - H-I (Box 11, Folder 473)
      - J-K (Box 11, Folder 474)
      - L-M (Box 11, Folder 475)
      - N-O (Box 11, Folder 476)
      - P-Q (Box 11, Folder 477)
      - R (Box 11, Folder 478)
      - S (Box 11, Folder 479)
      - T (Box 11, Folder 480)
      - U-V (Box 11, Folder 481)
      - W (Box 11, Folder 482)
      - X, Y, Z (Box 11, Folder 483)
    - Yale Alumni Athletics (Box 11, Folder 484)
    - Yale School of Drama- Notable Alumni (Box 11, Folder 485)
    - Epidemiology (Black Alumni) (Box 11, Folder 486)
    - Forestry Research (Box 11, Folder 487)
    - Law School Research (Box 11, Folder 488)
    - Yale Notable Alumni Literary (Box 11, Folder 489)
    - School of Management Research (Box 11, Folder 490)
    - School of Music Notable Alumni (Box 11, Folder 491)
    - School of Nursing Notable Alumni (Box 11, Folder 492)
    - Yale Honorary Degree Recipients (Box 11, Folder 493)
    - Major Yale Medals Prizes (Box 11, Folder 494)
    - Yale Medal Recipients (Box 11, Folder 495)
    - Honorary Degrees in Music Notable Figures (Box 11, Folder 496)
    - Yale Alumni Honorary Degree Recipients (Box 11, Folder 497)
    - Wilbur Cross Recipients (Box 11, Folder 498)
    - Government and Business Yale Alumni Research (Box 11, Folder 499)
    - Revolutionary War Officers (Box 11, Folder 500)
    - Yale Alumni in the Entertainment Industry (Box 11, Folder 501)
    - US Supreme Court Justices (Box 11, Folder 502)
    - Pulitzer Prize Winners, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 503)
    - Yale Alumni First College Pres Founders of Colleges (Box 11, Folder 504)
    - First Draft of Yale Alumni List (Box 11, Folder 505)
    - Leadership Directory Notable Alumni Research (Box 11, Folder 506)
    - History of Battel Chapel (Box 11, Folder 507)
    - Fourth Century Documents (Box 11, Folder 508)
    - Yale Bicentennial Information (Box 11, Folder 509)
    - Current Yale Students (Box 11, Folder 510)
    - Mory's (Box 11, Folder 511)
    - National Influence of Yale Graduates (Box 11, Folder 512)
    - Newberry Organ (Box 11, Folder 513)
    - Oldest School Research (Box 11, Folder 514)
    - Ranjan's Ideas (Box 11, Folder 515)
    - Trumbull College Research Information (Box 11, Folder 516)
    - Yale Alumni e-mail Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 517)
    - YAM Research (Box 11, Folder 518)
    - Yale Glee Club (Box 11, Folder 519)
    - Yale Symphony Orchestra (Box 11, Folder 520)
    - Yale Tour Information (Box 11, Folder 521)
    - Best Places to Research in New Haven (Box 11, Folder 522)
    - Ella Grasso (Box 11, Folder 523)
    - New Haven Architects (Box 11, Folder 524)
    - New Haven Articles (Box 11, Folder 525)
    - New Haven Green (Box 11, Folder 526)
    - New Haven. Grove Street Cemetery (Box 11, Folder 527)
    - Yale Alumni in New Haven (Box 11, Folder 528)
    - Yale New Haven Hospital Research (Box 11, Folder 529)
  - 300 Years of Creativity and Discovery
    - Attendees (Box 12, Folder 530)
    - Liasons (Box 12, Folder 531)
    - FAQ's (Box 12, Folder 532)
    - Lanman Center Meals (Box 12, Folder 533)
    - Meeting Space and Parking Lots (Box 12, Folder 534)
    - Operations Book (Box 12, Folder 535 - 536)
    - Post Card (Box 12, Folder 537)
    - Printing Needs (Box 12, Folder 538)
    - Program (Box 12, Folder 539)
    - Banners and Book Jackets (Box 12, Folder 540)
    - Attendees List (Box 12, Folder 541)
    - Invitation Lists (Box 12, Folder 542)
    - Leslie Baier (Box 12, Folder 543)
    - Program in Development (Box 12, Folder 544)
    - 300 Years -Ideas and Draft Program (Penny) (Box 12, Folder 545)
    - Program Material (Box 12, Folder 546)
    - Possible Speakers and Topics (Box 12, Folder 547)
    - Registration and Ticketing Website (Box 12, Folder 548)
    - President's Letter (Box 12, Folder 549)
    - Save the Date (Box 12, Folder 550)
    - Task and Venue Assignments (Preliminary) (Box 12, Folder 551)
    - Registration Information (Box 12, Folder 552)
    - Schedules (Alpha) (Box 12, Folder 553)
    - Schedules (Location or Task) (Box 12, Folder 554)
    - Speakers (Box 12, Folder 555)
    - Transportation Maps (Box 12, Folder 556)
    - Thank You's (Box 12, Folder 557)
    - Team Captains and Managers (Box 12, Folder 558)
  - Yale 300 Festival
    - Trolley Museum (Box 13, Folder 559)
    - Tercentennial Festival Spreadsheets (Box 13, Folder 560)
    - Tercentennial Festival (Box 13, Folder 561)
    - Map -Tercentennial Program (Box 13, Folder 562)
    - Thank you letters and correspondence to captains (Box 13, Folder 563)
    - Miscellaneous Historical Documents (Box 14, Folder 564)
  - TERCENTENNIAL GENERAL
    - Congratulation MIT (Box 15, Folder 565)
    - University of Pennsylvania (Box 15, Folder 566)
    - University of Tokyo (Box 15, Folder 567)
    - Princeton (Box 15, Folder 568)
    - Washington College (Box 15, Folder 569)
    - Western Connecticut State University (Box 15, Folder 570)
    - Vassar College (Box 15, Folder 571)
    - Middlebury College (Box 15, Folder 572)
    - Stationery Samples (Box 15, Folder 573)
    - Events Calendar (Box 15, Folder 574)
    - Planning Committee (Box 15, Folder 575)
    - Media Proposal (Box 15, Folder 576)
    - Progress Report (Box 15, Folder 577)
  - ANCILLARY EVENTS AND PUBLICATIONS
    - Art Gallery Exhibits (Box 15, Folder 578)
    - AYA Tours (Box 15, Folder 579)
    - Commencement (Box 15, Folder 580)
    - Commemorative Postcard (Box 15, Folder 581)
    - Connecticut Magazine (Box 15, Folder 582)
    - Devane Lectures (Box 15, Folder 583)
    - Holiday Card President Levin (Box 15, Folder 584)
    - Michelin Guide (Box 15, Folder 585)
    - New Haven Guide (Box 15, Folder 586)
    - Seal of the City (Box 15, Folder 587)
    - Stage Blue (Box 15, Folder 588)
    - Tetelman Fellowships (Box 15, Folder 589)
    - Yale School of Forestry (Box 15, Folder 590)
    - Yale Blue Trail Map (Box 15, Folder 591)
    - Up with Shout (Box 15, Folder 592)
    - A Yale Album (Box 15, Folder 593)
    - Yale Alumni Club (Box 15, Folder 594)
    - Stamp (Box 15, Folder 595)
  - OPENING Yale 300 - PRINT
    - Publicity Print Summary (Box 16, Folder 596)
    - Residential Colleges T Contest (Box 16, Folder 597)
    - Hostess Buttons (Box 16, Folder 598)
    - Posters -Opening Yale 300 (Box 16, Folder 599)
    - Publicity (Box 16, Folder 600)
    - MOMA Lapel Pins (Box 16, Folder 601)
    - Official Participant Tags (Box 16, Folder 602)
    - New Haven Register Insert (Box 16, Folder 603)
    - Mailer (Box 16, Folder 604)
    - Table Tents -Students (Box 16, Folder 605)
    - Lollipops (Box 16, Folder 606)
    - Blues Clues Contest (Box 16, Folder 607)
    - Yale Bulletin (Box 16, Folder 608)
  - APRIL WEEKEND
    - Mailings (Box 16, Folder 609)
    - Registration Order form (Box 16, Folder 610)
    - Registration Packet (Box 16, Folder 611)
    - Program- Blue Book (Box 16, Folder 612)
    - Student Tickets (Box 16, Folder 613)
    - Signage (Box 16, Folder 614)
    - Plenary Sessions (Box 16, Folder 615)
    - Yale Medal Luncheon (Box 16, Folder 616)
    - Light Blue Concert (Box 16, Folder 617)
    - Royal Blue Concert (Box 16, Folder 618)
  - CELEBRATE Yale 300 October 5, 2001
    - New York Times, 2001 September 11 (Box 16, Folder 619)
    - Yale Bowl Decorations (Box 16, Folder 620)
    - Larc Proposal (Box 16, Folder 621)
    - Invitations (Box 16, Folder 622)
    - Confirmation Program (Box 16, Folder 623)
    - Visiting Presidents - Info (Box 16, Folder 624)
    - Stationery (Box 16, Folder 625)
    - Exploding Y Designs (Box 16, Folder 626)
    - Table Tents (Box 16, Folder 627)
    - Tickets (Box 16, Folder 628)
    - Campus Posters (Box 16, Folder 629)
    - Symposium (Box 16, Folder 630)
    - Commemorative Pin (Box 16, Folder 631)
    - Convocation Program (Box 16, Folder 632)
    - General Schedule (Box 16, Folder 633)
    - Larc Signage (Box 16, Folder 634)
    - Yale Bowl Signs (Box 16, Folder 635)
    - Festival -Pre Program (Box 16, Folder 636)
    - Program (Box 16, Folder 637)
    - Presidents Levin Welcome (Box 16, Folder 638)
    - Handkerchiefs (Box 16, Folder 639)
    - Pepsi Commemorative Gift (Box 16, Folder 640)
    - Clinton's Address (Box 16, Folder 641)
    - Gift for Workers -Bulldog /Watch/ Photo (Box 16, Folder 642)
    - Yale 300 Sign (Box 16, Folder 643)
    - CD Music at Yale (Box 16, Folder 644)
    - License Plate (Box 16, Folder 645)
    - LARC Proposed site plan for event originally scheduled for Cross Campus, 2001 October (Box 17, Folder 646)
    - Final Seating Plan for Tercentennial Event at Yale Bowl, 2001 October 5 (Box 17, Folder 647)
    - Proposed Seating Plan for Tercentennial Event at Yale Bowl, 2001 October 5 (Box 17, Folder 648)
    - Original Concept for Stage and Seating of Tercentennial Event at Yale Bowl (laminated), 2001 October 5 (Box 17, Folder 649)
    - Poster of Harkness Tower as rendered in a woodcut by Jacques Hnizdovsky (Box 17, Folder 650)
  - Posters
    - Democratic Vistas (Box 18, Folder 651)
    - Preaching in the New Millennium (Box 18, Folder 652)
    - Campus Poster - (Box 18, Folder 653)
    - Telelman Fellowship (Box 18, Folder 654)
    - 4 posters not produced (Box 18, Folder 655)
    - Beginning with the Humanities (Box 18, Folder 656)
    - Royal Blue (Box 18, Folder 657)
    - Bowl Designs (Box 18, Folder 658)
  - 6 Samples of Commemorative Medals (Box 19, Folder 659)
  - Archival Notebook, 2001 April (Box 20, Folder 660)
  - Archival Notebook, 2001 October (Box 20, Folder 661)
  - Final Data on Guests, 2001 April (Box 20, Folder 662)
  - Inauguration Notes from 1993 (Box 20, Folder 663)
  - LARC Proposed plans for Oct. 2001 event on Cross Campus (Box 20, Folder 664)
  - Assorted (Box 20, Folder 665)
  - Library and Book notes (Box 20, Folder 666)
  - Research Misc. (Box 20, Folder 667)
  - Arms (Box 20, Folder 668)
  - Wales (Box 20, Folder 669)
  - Yale name lineage (Box 20, Folder 670)
  - Articles (Box 20, Folder 671)
  - Correspondence (Box 20, Folder 672)
  - Images and Photos (Box 20, Folder 673)
  - Misc. Yale Publications (Box 20, Folder 674)
  - Boola Boola, Hero for Daisy, and WAY Beyond materials, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 675)
  - Research on Women, Memo to President for future funding, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 676)
  - Gender Matters conference materials and correspondence, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 677)
  - Boola Boola…Yale Goes Coed, movie for G Matter, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 678)
- Records the Tercentennial Office [computer files], 1999-2001; Accession 2002-A-098
  - Records the Tercentennial Office, computer files (DOC, MDB, PDF, XLS, TIFF), 1999-2001
    General note
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
- Website for Yale's 300th anniversary [computer files], 2000-2001; Accession 2002-A-102
  The materials are open for research.
  - Website for Yale's 300th anniversary, 2000-2001; computer files (CSS, GIF, HTML, JPEG, PDF)
- Speech by Robin Winks, "Yale, America, and the World, 2101", 2001; Accession 2002-A-103
  - Speech by Robin Winks, "Yale, America, and the World, 2101", 2001; computer file (DOC)
- Poem by John Hollander celebrating Yale's 300th anniversary titled "Commemorative Stanzas.", Accession 2002-A-107
  - Poem by John Hollander celebrating Yale's 300th anniversary titled "Commemorative Stanzas" (Box 1)
- Recognition of Yale's 300th anniversary by the University of the Philippines, 2001; Accession 2002-A-114
  - Recognition of Yale's 300th anniversary by the University of the Philippines, 2001 (Box 1)
- Program pamphlet celebrating Abraham Pierson and Yale's 300th, in Clinton, CT, 2001; Accession 2002-A-115
  - Program pamphlet celebrating Abraham Pierson and Yale's 300th, in Clinton, CT, 2001 (Box 1)
- Yale's 300th anniversary [videorecordings], 2000-2001; Accession 2003-A-118
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Yale Tercentennial: 300 Years of Creativity and Discovery, 2001 April 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - WTNH-TV 8, Yale: Behind the Ivy, [commerically produced], 2000 December 14; 1 (Box 2)
  - Opening Yale 300, 2000 October 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - WTNH-TV8, Celebrate Yale 300, [commerically-produced], 2001 October 5; 1 (Box 4)
  - William Jefferson Clinton, Tercentennial Symposium, 2001 October 5; videotape (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Yale University Tercentennial Gala, Yale Bowl, 2001 October; 1 (Box 6)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 6U)
  - DeVane Lecture Series: "Democratic Vistas"
    - Ian Shapiro, Democracy and Distribution, videotape (VHS), videotape (VHS) (Box 7)
    - Bruce Ackerman, The Death of Citizenship, videotape (VHS), 2001 February 20 (Box 8)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 8U)
    - Richard C. Levin, Democracy and the Market, videotape (VHS), videotape (VHS) (Box 9)
    - John Lewis Gaddis, Democracy and Foreign Policy, videotape (VHS), 2001 April 17; videotape (VHS) (Box 10)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 10U)
    - Richard Benson, Pictures for the People, videotape (VHS), 2001 May 1; videotape (VHS) (Box 11)
    - Anthony Kronman, The Democratic Soul, videotape (VHS), 2001 January 9; videotape (VHS) (Box 12)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 12U)
    - David Bromwich, Lincoln and Whitman as Representative Americans, videotape (VHS), 2001 January 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 13)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 13U)
    - Mahzarin Banaji, Paradoxes of Mind and Society, videotape (VHS), 2001 January 23; videotape (VHS) (Box 14)
    - Michael Denning, Neither Capitalist nor American: The Democracy as a Social Movement, videotape (VHS), 2001 February 13; videotape (VHS) (Box 15)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 15U)
    - Joan A. Steitz, American Democracy and the Origins of the Biomedical Revolution, videotape (VHS), 2001 February 27; videotape (VHS) (Box 16)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 16U)
    - David Gelernter, Democracy and the Computer, videotape (VHS), 2001 March 20; videotape (VHS) (Box 17)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 17U)
    - Richard Brodhead, Democracy and Education, videotape (VHS), 2001 March 20 (Box 18)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 18U)
    - Nancy F. Cott, Democracy and the Family, videotape (VHS), 2001 April 3; videotape (VHS) (Box 19)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 19U)
    - Stephen L. Carter, Democracy and Foreign Policy, videotape (VHS), 2001 April 10; videotape (VHS) (Box 20)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 20U)
    - James C. Scott, Meritocracy and Democracy, videotape (VHS), 2001 April 24; videotape (VHS) (Box 21)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 21U)
    - "Light Blue: the Lighter Side of Yale, A Tercentennial Tribute", 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 22)
    - "300 Years: A Tercentennnial Tribute, Yale University, 1701-2001", videotape (VHS) (Box 23)
- Research records and administrative files from the Yale Tercentennial Program, circa 2001; Accession 2004-A-160
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2037
  - Tax Exempt (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vanwyck, Anna (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vision Media (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Larc (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Larc Event (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Consolidated Transaction detail report (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Trade mark (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Unigraphics (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Tickets.com (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tyco (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Vistas (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - W-9s (Tercentennial) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - WFF invoices (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - WSHU / WELI / WEBE (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - WTNH -Channel 8 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Website access log (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Woolsey Hall (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yale Club (NYC) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - YAM (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Yale Microcomputer Support Center (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Yale Daily News (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Yandle, Martha (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Yale University Press (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Yale Trail (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Yale University Printer (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - YUP (press) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Invoices (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Consolidated Transaction Detail Report (Box 1, Folder 30 - 38)
  - Budget Projections (Box 2, Folder 39 - 42)
  - Budget Additions (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Three Centuries of Creativity and Discovery (Box 2, Folder 44 - 45)
  - Flink, Stanley (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Archives 300 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Alumni Directory (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - October 2001 weekend (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Brewster Book (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Commencement Expenses (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - History Fund (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Liability Insurance (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Lectures (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Modlin (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Oren Book (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Reference Series (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Smith Book (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Special Projects (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Garry Reeder (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Shapiro, Harold (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Salaries (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Salary Ranges (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Misc. Research Materials (Box 3)
  - Misc. Research Materials (Box 4)
  - Images (Photographs, slides, proof sheets) (Box 5)
  - Digital images for promotional materials and Websites (Box 6–15)
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
- Yale Tercentennial [videorecordings], 2000-2001; Accession 2006-A-248
  - "Yale Tercentennial: 300 Years of Creativity and Discovery", 2001 April 21; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - "Yale 300: Behind the Ivy," WTNH-TV, 2000 December 14; commercially-produced videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - "Yale: 300 Years," WTNH-TV?, undated; commercially-produced videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
- Photographs and event information from Yale University's 300th anniversary commemoration, 2001; Accession 2007-A-068
  - Event Information, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 6)
  - Publications, 2001 (Box 2)
- 2001: The Tercentennial of Yale: A Framework by the Tercentennial Planning Committee, circa 1997; Accession 2007-A-183
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2033
  - 2001: The Tercentennial of Yale: A Framework by the Tercentennial Planning Committee, circa 1997 (Box 1)
- Tercentennial news clippings and official statement of Governor John Rowland, 2001; Accession 2008-A-018
  - Advertising, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Events, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Guests, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Labor issues, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Official statement of Governor John G. Rowland, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pre-event publicity, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Post-event articles and editorials, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale Bowl celebration, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Yale Tercentennial Celebration in Asia, 2000-2002; Accession 2012-A-029
  - Administrative records
    - Planning Committee -- Agendas, budgets, correspondence, notes, and event ephemera, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - "Project Report", 2001 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brochures and invitation, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia, Circa 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs
    - Negatives, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Prints, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Digital Photographs, 1128 (Box 6–16)
  - Videorecordings
    - Behind the Ivy: Yale Tercentennial, Circa 2001; 1 (Box 3)
    - Celebrate Yale 300, 2001; 1 (Box 4)
      General
      Broadcast on 5 October 2001.
    - Mr. Richard Levin -- President, Yale University, 2001 May 2; 1 (Box 5)
      - CNN Asia Business Morning, 2001 May 2
      - CNBC Squawk Box, 2001 May 3
- Yale Tercentennial Celebration in Asia, 2001; Accession 2018-A-0008
  - Correspondence and event ephemera, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)